# **DAVIDE GHIOTTO**

November, 2021

(VI) Italy | dghiotto.careers@gmail.com | linkedin: davide-ghiotto | github: davide97g | portfolio: davideghiotto.it

# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### **CARRIER PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer with 22 months of experience implementing custom Angular Web Applications and core Java microservices, for large scale use in the banking sector. Developed reusable components and effective models to keep the pace with continuous delivery of high quality products. Managed a massive database migration activity.

Core competences include: Angular, Vuejs, Java, Node.js, web API, TypeScript, Firebase, JavaScript, SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Spring, Git, HTML, CSS, Sass.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Namirial

October 2021 to present

R&D Developer

Full stack R&D developer building cross-platform application with Vuejs, Electron and .Net.

Zucchetti S.p.A

April 2021 to July 2021

Data Scientist

Built an online interactive platform for the introduction of data science topics inside the company. Developed custom algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning

- Organized the architecture for a wide online library of machine-learning algorithms implemented in JavaScript
- Developed custom machine-learning algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning, targeting the specific problems of the company

# Reply S.p.A - Cluster & Core Financial Services

Nov 2019 to Oct 2021

Full Stack Developer & Database Manager

Developed complete Angular Web Applications, integrated with backend Java API, in a microservice oriented architecture, in order to build a large scale platform capable of handling the complexity of financial services world.

Managed a massive database migration to a SQL Server environment.

Implemented high quality code to speed up further developments and lower maintenance work in a continuous delivery environment.

- Created a generalized conceptual model to efficiently handle user interactions and data flow leading to an uniformed solution capable of avoid potential error situations and repetitive work
- Implemented a decentralized error handling strategy to avoid single point of failure with an increased reliability of the
- Improved data retrieval time through careful analysis and optimization of database's requests along with asynchronous client-side code
- Accelerated the procedure of database migration thanks to the development of scripts for automated quality control

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Web technologies: Angular, Vuejs, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Sass
- Backend technologies: Nodejs, Java, Python, Spring
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, POSTGRES, ORACLE
- Cloud Platform: Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku
- Data Science: R, Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn
- Versioning: Git, Github, Bitbucket

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science

### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree Data Science

University of Study of Padua

110L/110

University of Study of Padua

110L/110

2016-2019

**Highschool Graduation** 

Liceo Scientifico Statale G.B. Quadri

2011-2016

2019-2021

87/100

# **CERTIFICATES**

• **B2 First**, 2015

#### OTHER SKILLS

**Languages** English: professional proficiency. Italian: native.